Silence will fall.
River: The Doctor we saw on
the beach was a future version.
Amy: All that's still going to
happen, he's still going to die?
I'm pregnant.
Whatever happens --
we will find you.
The whole time I thought
I was on the TARDIS,
I was really here?
They've taken Amy and our baby.
We're going after her.
Amelia Pond!
Get your coat!
Vastra: Is Melody human?
Of course she is.
Look closer --
human plus Time Lord.
What is she?
Hope in this endless,
bitter war.
Against who?
Against you,
Doctor.
River: And now,
they've taken a child --
and they're going to
turn her into a weapon,
just to bring you down.
Who are you?
Why are you in prison?
Who did you kill?
Tell me
who you are.
I am telling you.
Rory and Amy, I know where
to find your daughter
and, on my life,
she will be safe.
River: The Doctor will
find your daughter
and he will care for her,
whatever it takes.
[ Crying ]
It's me.
I'm your daughter.
[ Birds chirping ]
Okay, left,
sharp turn.
Okay, right --
no, no, no, I mean left!
No, very right, right,
I definitely meant right.
Aah!
Now loop-the-loop.
Stop! Stop!
Ooh!
Seriously?
Well, you never
answer your phone.
Okay, you've had
all summer.
Have you found her?
Have you found Melody?
You know
who she grows up
to be,
so you know
I will find her.
But you haven't,
yet?
Hang on.
What's this bit?
Amy:
That wasn't us.
Um --
no, I don't --
[ gunning engine ]
Aah!
Aah! Aah!
You said
he was funny.
You never said
he was hot.
- Mels!
- What are you doing here?
Following you.
What do you think?
Rory: Um, where did you
get the car?
It's mine.
[ Wailing sirens pass ]
Uh, -ish.
Amy: Oh, Mels, not again.
You can't keep doing this.
You're going to end up in prison.
Sorry.
Hello. Doctor
not following this.
Doctor very lost.
You never said
I was hot?
Is that
the phone box?
The bigger-on-the-inside
phone box.
Oh, time travel.
That's just
brilliant.
Yeah, I've heard
a lot about you.
I'm their best mate.
Then why
don't I know you?
I danced with everyone
at the wedding.
The women
were all brilliant.
The men were
a bit shy.
I don't do weddings.
[ Wailing sirens
approach ]
And that's me,
out of time.
[ Cocks handgun ]
Amy: Mels!
What are you doing?
For God's sake!
I need
out of here, now.
Anywhere
in particular?
Well, let's see --
you've got a time machine,
I've got a gun.
What the hell --
let's kill Hitler.
♪ Doctor Who 6x08 ♪
Let's Kill Hitler
Original Air Date on August 26, 2011
== sync, corrected by elderman ==
Is he hot?
No, he's funny.
But how can he
travel in time?
'Cause he's got
a time machine, stupid.
I thought we were
playing hide and seek.
I've been hiding
for hours.
Well -- [sigh] we just
haven't found you yet.
O-kay.
- Hi, Mels.
- Hi, Rory.
Mels, did you not
understand the question?
I'm asking you why
the Titanic sank.
Because the Doctor
didn't save it.
Except, you don't know
about the Doctor
because you're stupid.
Amelia: Why are you
always in trouble?
You're the most
in trouble
in the whole school,
except for boys.
And you.
I count as a boy.
Am I getting warm?
Yes, Rory.
[ Sighing ]
Mels.
A significant factor
in Hitler's rise to power
was the fact that
the Doctor didn't stop him.
[ Bell rings ]
Amy: You can't keep
doing this.
Mels!
It was late.
I took a bus.
- You stole a bus.
- Who steals a bus?
I returned it.
You drove it through
the Botanical Gardens.
Shortcut.
Why can't you just
act like a person, hmm,
like a normal,
legal person?
I dunno.
Maybe I need a Doctor.
Stop it.
Uh, I'd better go.
I'm on earlies tomorrow.
It's all right
for you.
You've got Mr. Perfect
keeping you right.
He's not even real,
just a stupid dream
when I was a kid.
No, I wasn't talking
about him.
What, Rory?
How have I
got Rory?
Yeah, how --
how has she
got me?
He's not mine.
No...No.
I'm not hers.
Oh, come on, seriously,
it's got to be you two.
Oh, cut to the song.
It's getting boring.
Nice thought, okay?
But completely impossible.
Yeah, impossible.
I'd love to,
he's gorgeous,
he's my favorite guy,
but he's, you know...
- A friend.
- Gay.
I'm not gay.
Yes, you are.
No.
No, I'm not.
Of course you are.
Don't be stupid.
In the whole time I've known
you, when have you shown
the slightest interest
in a girl?
Penny in the air.
I mean, I've known you
for, what, 10 years?
I've seen you
practically every day.
Name one girl
you've paid
the slightest
bit of attention to.
[ Laughs ]
Oh, my God!
Rory!
And the penny drops.
Catch you later,
time boy.
[ Gunshot ]
The Doctor: You shot it!
You shot my TARDIS!
You shot the console!
It's your fault!
Aah!
How is it my fault?!
You said guns didn't
work in this place.
You said we're in a state
of temporal grace!
That was a clever lie,
you idiot!
Anyone can tell that was
a clever lie!
Amy: Ro...Ry!
[ Whirring ]
Okay,
do we like him?
Costume want to know
about the suit.
Just color and shape.
Don't need anything detachable.
Musculature:
Good to go.
- Oh, that's quick.
- They're showing off.
Art department wants
to talk about skin tone.
Yes, I do. I don't
trust the sensors.
I want to take
a look myself.
We're in a hurry.
We're not trying
to win an award.
Yeah, that's what you said
when you made Rasputin green.
Okay, get your fat one
you there. Run!
Yes, Captain.
Harriet's going
to eyeball.
Everyone else,
good to go, please.
What do you want?
What are you doing?
Musculature...
online.
5'11", confirmed.
Harriet, are you
up there yet?
[ Beeping ]
[ Alarm blares ]
Welcome.
You are unauthorized.
Your death will now be
implemented.
Harriet, have you updated
your privileges?
Yes, of course
I have.
[ Beeping ]
Look, I'm staff, see?
Look, staff!
You are authorized.
Your existence
will continue.
I don't understand.
Carter:
Harriet, the shape!
Five seconds
to eyeball.
Shapes 44 to 89,
peaking at 60.
Standard density.
He's sweating a bit,
so compensate.
What are you?
All hands, prepare
for tessellation.
Prepare for tessellation.
[ Gasping ]
[ Shuddering ]
Okay.
Clean up.
Aah! Aaaahhh!
[ Panting ]
Carter:
Who is he?
Anita:
Erik Zimmerman,
loyal member
of the Nazi party,
guilty of category 3
hate crimes.
Well, then,
leave him
to the antibodies.
Antibody:
Welcome.
You are
unauthorized.
Your death will now be
implemented.
[ Shuddering ]
Welcome.
You will experience
a tingling sensation
and then death.
Remain calm while
your life is extracted.
Aaaaaaaah!
What do you want?
Who let you
in here?
What's wrong with
the shock absorbers?
Problem
in the knees.
Let's hope we don't
have to run.
As Zimmerman:
Do not call for help.
This room has been
soundscreened.
You have been found
guilty.
Justice mode
activating.
Ahhhh!
Hang on! This is 1938.
We're too early.
We need to go later
in his timestream.
Something else.
We've got incoming!
Onscreen.
[ TARDIS engines ]
What the hell
is that?!
Out, out, out!
Everybody, out!
Don't breathe the smoke,
just get out!
Amy: Where are we?!
A room!
Rory: What room?!
I don't know what room --
I haven't memorized
every room in the universe
yet -- I had yesterday off.
Mels, don't go
in there!
Oi!
Bad smoke.
Don't breathe
the bad, bad smoke.
Bad, deadly smoke because
somebody shot my TARDIS!
Doctor, this guy,
I think he's hurt.
[ Alarm blaring ]
Carter: Transmit normal life signs.
Jim: Artificial
gravity holding,
but we should get
upright when we can.
No, hang on.
No, he's fine.
Ooh! Hello.
Sorry,
is this your office?
Had a sort of collision
with my...vehicle.
Faults on both sides.
Let's say no more about...
It.
[ Gasp ]
Is that...? No, it
can't be, Doctor-r-r.
Thank you,
whoever you are.
I think you have just
saved my life.
Believe me,
it was an accident.
What is this thing?
What did he mean,
we just saved his life?
We could not have just
saved Hitler.
You see? You see?
Contrast.
It never goes
to plan.
This box --
what is it?
It's a police telephone
box from London, England.
That's right, Adolf:
The British are coming.
No.
Stop him!
Damage report!
Sit still,
shut up.
- Are you okay?
- Yes.
[ Echoing as Zimmerman ]
Yes. Yes, I'm fine.
I think he missed.
- He was going to kill me.
- Shut up, Hitler!
Rory, take Hitler and put him
in that cupboard over there.
Now, do it.
Right. Putting Hitler
in the cupboard.
Cupboard, Hitler.
Hitler, cupboard.
Come on.
But I am
the Fuhrer!
Right, in you go!
Who are you?
Are you okay?
Alice: Sir,
what do we do now?
Jim: Suggestion: We should
go into surveillance mode.
Agreed.
Let's faint.
Oh,
I...
[ Thud ]
I think
he just fainted.
Yes, that was
a faint.
A perfect faint.
Mels?
Mels: Hitler.
What about him?
Lousy shot.
Mels! Mels!
Rory!
No, no, no, no,
no, no.
All right, we got to
stop the bleeding.
Sir,
that blue box --
I've got a match.
We're trying to bag
war criminals --
we've got the
biggest one, ever,
right under
our noses.
Forget Hitler.
If we take this one down,
the Justice Department
will give us the rest
of the year off.
Are you sure?
There's no question.
It's her.
How bad is it, Rory?
What can we do?
Rory: Just
keep her conscious.
Stay with us, Mels!
Hey, look at me.
Just hold on.
I used to
dream about you.
All those stories
Amy used to tell me.
What stories?
Tell me what stories.
Vampires in Venice,
that's --
When I was...little,
I was going to
marry you.
Good idea, let's get married --
you stay alive
and I'll marry you,
deal? Deal?
Shouldn't you ask
my parents' permission?
As soon as you're well,
I'll get them on the phone.
Might as well
do it now.
Since they're both
right here.
Penny in the air.
Penny drops.
What the hell
is going on?
Back, back, back, back,
get back!
The last time
I did this,
I ended up a toddler
in the middle
of New York.
Okay, Doctor,
explain what is
happening, please.
"Mels," short for...
Melody.
Yeah, I named my daughter
after her.
You named
your daughter
after your daughter.
Mels: It took me years
to find you two.
I'm so glad I did.
You see?
It all worked out,
in the end, didn't it?
You got to raise me,
after all.
You're Melody?
But if she's Melody, that
means that she's also --
Oh, shut up, Dad,
I'm focusing
on a dress size.
Aaaaaaaaaaaaah!
[ Wailing ]
[ Gasp ]
Oh! Ohh!
Ah!
[ Shudders ]
Right,
let's see, then.
Ooh! It's all going on
down there, isn't it?
The hair!
[ Gasp ]
It just doesn't stop,
does it?
Look at that!
Everything changes.
Oh, but I love it.
I love it!
I'm all sort of...
Mature.
Hello, Benjamin.
Who's Benjamin?
The teeth.
The teeth, the teeth.
Oh, look at them!
[ Laughs ]
Watch out,
that bow-tie.
Excuse me,
you lot,
I need
to weigh myself.
That's...
Melody.
[ Sniff ]
It's
River Song.
Who's
River Song?
Spoilers.
"Spoilers"?
What spoilers?
Hang on, just something
I have to check.
Does anybody else
find this day
just a bit
difficult?
I'm getting this sort of
banging in my head.
Yeah, I think that's
Hitler, in the cupboard.
That's
not helping.
This isn't the River Song
we know, yet.
This is her,
right at the start.
She doesn't even know
her name.
Melody: Ah!
That's magnificent!
I'm going to wear lots
of jumpers.
Well, it's her,
all right,
Melody Pond,
the woman who kills
the Doctor.
Well, now, enough
of all that.
[ Cocking handgun ]
Down to business.
Oh, hello.
I thought we were
getting married.
I told you --
I'm not
a wedding person.
Doctor, what is she doing?
What she's programmed to.
Rory: And where did
she get the gun?
"Hello, Benjamin."
Hello, Benjamin.
You noticed.
[ Dryfiring ]
Of course I noticed.
Aaaaaaaaaaaaah!
[ Dryfires ]
As soon as I knew you were
coming, I tidied up a bit.
[ Clatter ]
I know you did.
Watch out,
that bow-tie.
I know you know.
Goodness, is killing you
going to take all day?
Why?
Are you busy?
Oh, I'm not
complaining.
[ Pulsing ]
If you were
in a hurry,
you could've killed me
in the cornfield.
We'd only just met.
I'm a psychopath.
I'm not rude.
No-no-no! Aah!
[ Blows ]
Amy: You are not
a psychopath.
Why would she be
a psychopath?
[ Clatter ]
Oh, mummy,
mummy,
pay attention.
I was trained
and conditioned
for one purpose --
I was born
to kill the Doctor.
Demons Run.
Remember?
This is what
they were building:
My bespoke
psychopath.
I'm all yours,
sweetie.
Only River Song gets
to call me that.
- And who's River Song?
- An old friend of mine.
Stupid name.
[ Gasp ]
Look at that.
Berlin,
on the eve of war.
A whole world, about
to tear itself apart.
Now, that's my kind
of town.
Mum, dad,
don't follow me
and, yes,
that is a warning.
No warning for me,
then?
No need, my love.
The deed is done
and so are you.
Doctor,
what's wrong?
What --
what have you done?
River.
Oh, "River,
River, River."
More than a friend,
I think.
What have you done?!
Ohh!
It was never going to be
a gun for you, Doctor,
the man of peace,
who understands every
kind of warfare,
except, perhaps,
the cruelest.
I'm all yours,
sweetie.
Kiss-kiss.
Rory: What's wrong with you?
What's she done to you?
Poisoned me.
But I'm fine.
Well, no, I'm dying.
But I've got a plan.
What plan?
Not dying.
See? Fine.
Scanning him.
He's dying,
all right.
But he can't be.
Aggggh!
Okay, what do we do?
How do we help you?
Take this. The TARDIS
can home in on it.
Now, go,
get after her.
Melody: Oi!
[ Exclaiming ]
[ Cocking weapons ]
Hello, boys.
You said the smoke
was deadly.
No, the smoke's fine.
The poison
will kill me, first.
Now, get after River.
I don't understand, okay?
One minute, she's
going to marry you,
and then, she's
going to kill you.
Well, but she's been
brainwashed.
It all makes sense.
Plus, she's a woman.
Oh, shut up,
I'm dying.
[ Coughing ]
Extractor fans on!
Oh! That works.
What are you
doing here?
Well, I was on my way
to this gay, gypsy bar mitzah
for the disabled
when I suddenly thought,
"Gosh, the Third Reich's
a bit rubbish.
I think I'll kill
the Fuhrer."
Who's with me?
Shoot her.
[ Firing ] No!
[ Shell casings
clatter ]
Tip for you all --
never shoot a girl
while she's regenerating.
Aaaah! Aaaah!
[ Laughs ]
[ Soldier exclaims ]
Ahh!
Now, that hit the spot.
Thanks, boys.
Call me.
Amy: What
are you doing?
New body,
new town --
I'm going shopping.
Look, I know
how this looks.
Let me explain everything,
from the beginning.
Heil!
Come on!
Can you ride
a motorbike?
I expect so.
It's that sort of day.
[ Whirring ]
Okay, this time,
let's do the bike, too.
You see?
He can't be dying.
But the Doctor is confirmed
deceased. We have his records.
But he doesn't
die here.
He dies in Utah,
by Lake Silencio,
April 22, 2011.
Time can be rewritten.
Remember Kennedy?
This time can't.
It's a confirmed
fixed point.
The Doctor must always
die exactly then.
He always has,
he always will.
Then someone screwed up,
because he's dying right now.
Shutting down.
I need an interface.
Voice interface.
Come on, emergency.
Voice interface
enabled.
No, no, no, no, no, no.
Give me someone I like.
Oh! Thanks!
Give me guilt.
Also guilt.
More guilt!
Ah! Ahh!
[Crying] Come on,
there must be someone left
in the Universe
I haven't screwed up yet.
Ah!
Amelia: Voice
interface enabled.
Oh.
Oh!
Amelia Pond,
before I got it
all wrong.
My sweet,
little Amelia.
I am not Amelia Pond.
I am a voice interface.
Hey, let's run away
and have adventures.
Come along, Pond.
I am not Amelia Pond.
I am a voice interface.
You are
so Scottish.
How am I doing?
Your system has been
contaminated
by the poison
of the Judas tree.
You will be dead
in 32 minutes.
Okay, so, basically,
better regenerate,
that's what
you're saying.
Regeneration:
Disabled.
You will be dead
in 32 minutes.
Unless I'm cured!
Yeah?
There is no cure.
You will be dead
in 32 minutes.
Why do you keep
saying that?
Because you will be dead
in 32 minutes.
You see?
There you go again,
basically skipping
31 whole minutes
when I'm
absolutely fine.
Scottish,
that's all I'm saying.
You will be fine
for 31 minutes.
You will be dead
in 32 minutes.
Scotland was never
conquered, anyway, you know.
Not even a Shetland.
River needs me.
She's only just beginning.
I can't die now.
You will not
die now.
You will die
in 32 minutes.
"I'm going out
in the first round!"
Ring any bells?
Aah-aah-aah-aah!
Okay.
Need something
for the pain now.
[ Crying ]
Come on, Amelia.
It's me.
Please.
I am not Amelia Pond.
I am a voice interface.
Amelia,
listen to me --
I can be brave
for you,
but you have got to
tell me how.
I am not Amelia Pond.
I am a voice interface.
Amelia.
Please.
Help me.
Fish fingers
and custard.
What did you say?
Ha ha ha.
Fish fingers
and custard.
[ Laughs ]
Ah!
Ohh!
Amelia Pond.
Fish...Fingers...
and custard.
Fish...
Fingers
and...
Custard!
[ Playing Pachabel's
"Canon in D" ]
Mmm!
Gut.
[ Automatic-weapons
fire ]
Aah!
Ladies and gentlemen,
I don't have
a thing to wear.
[ Chuckling ]
Hmm.
Take off your clothes.
♪
Okay, all of Berlin.
How do we find her?
I don't know.
Look for...clues.
Clues?
What kind of "clues"?
Shut up.
[ Screaming ]
O-kay.
No.
[ Whirring ]
Hmm,
now look at that.
Now, that's fun, ha,
from every angle.
Now, dear,
I told you not
to follow me.
[ Gasp ]
Okay.
Okay, I'm trapped
inside a giant robot
replica of my wife.
I'm really trying not to
see this as a metaphor.
Amy: How can we be
in here? How do we fit?
Miniaturization
ray.
How would you
know that?
Well, there was a ray
and we were miniaturized.
[ Whirring ]
Welcome.
You are unauthorized.
Your death will now be
implemented.
Um, what's that?
Uh, I don't know.
It's in your head.
Please remain calm while
your life is terminated.
We come in peace.
- Ha ha, when has that ever worked?
- Oh, shut up.
Please cooperate
in your officially
sanctioned termination.
It is normal to experience fear
during your incineration.
Stop! Or I'll sonic.
What are you doing?
I dunno.
Okay, psychic interface.
Just point and think.
- I know, but what do I think?
- I don't know!
It's okay.
Stay still
and don't move.
Here.
Privileges activated.
See? Activated.
You are authorized.
Your existence
will continue.
You can put
your hands down.
This is
Justice Department
vehicle 6018.
You're not guilty
of anything.
Welcome aboard
the Teselecta.
I might take the age
down a little,
just gradually,
to freak
people out.
You killed
the Doctor.
Oh, yes,
I know, dear.
I hope you're not going to
keep on about it.
Ooh, regeneration.
It's a whole new
coloring to work with.
[ Chuckle ]
[ Whirring ]
You killed the Doctor
on the orders
of the movement known
as the Silence,
an academy
of the question.
You accept and know
this to be true?
Quite honestly,
I don't really remember.
It was all a bit of
a jumble.
No! No-o-o!
Get off me-e-e!
Sorry, did you say
she killed the Doctor?
The Doctor?
Doctor Who?
You said he was dying.
Anita: He is.
When you're done here,
your memories will be wiped
and you'll be able to --
- Doctor?
Melody:
You're dying
and you stopped
to change?
Oh, you should always waste time
when you don't have any.
Time is not
the boss of you.
Rule 408.
Amelia Pond,
judgment death machine.
Why am I not surprised?
Sonic cane.
Are you serious?
Never knowingly.
Never knowingly be
serious.
Rule 27. You might want
to write these down.
Oh, it's a robot!
With 423 life signs
inside.
A robot worked
by tiny people.
Love it.
But how did you all get
in there, though?
Bigger on the inside?
No, basic miniaturization
sustained
by a compression
field -- ooh!
Watch what you eat.
It'll get you every time.
Amy, if you and Rory
are okay,
signal me.
[ Pulsing ]
Thanking you.
Carter:
Why'd you do that?
Aaaaah!
Aah-I'm so sorry!
Leg went to sleep.
Just had a quick
left-leg power nap.
I forgot I had one
scheduled.
Actually,
I'd better sit down.
I think I heard
the right one yawning.
Aaah!
Aaaaah!
Don't you touch her!
Do not harm her, in any way!
Ohh!
[ Echoing as Amy ]
Why would you care?
She's the woman
who kills you.
I'm not dead.
You're dying.
Well, at least I'm not
a time-traveling,
shapeshifting robot
operated by
miniaturized,
cross people,
which, I have
got to admit,
I didn't see coming.
[ Melody moaning ]
What do you want
with her?
She's Melody Pond.
According
to our records,
the woman who kills
the Doctor.
And I'm the Doctor,
so what's it
got to do with you?
[ Feedback whines ]
Throughout history,
many criminals
have gone unpunished
in their lifetimes.
Time travel has...
Responsibilities.
[ Laughs ]
What?
You got yourselves
time travel,
so you decided
to punish dead people?
We don't kill them,
we extract them
near the end of their
established timelines.
And then what?
Give them hell.
I'd ask you
who you think you are,
but I think the answer
is pretty obvious.
So who do you think
I am, huh?
"The woman who killed
the Doctor."
It sounds like you've got
my biography in there.
I'd love a peek.
Our records office
is sealed to the public.
Foreknowledge
is dangerous.
Yeah, well, I'll be
dead in three minutes.
There isn't much
foreknowledge left.
Sorry,
can't do that.
That man is
my best friend.
That woman is
my daughter.
You give him
anything he wants.
If she's family,
she has privileges.
[ Beeping ]
Say "Access personal
records: The Doctor."
Access
personal records:
The Doctor.
Records available.
[ Grunt ]
Question.
I'm dying.
- Who wants me dead?
- The Silence.
What is the silence?
Why's it called that?
What does it mean?
The Silence
is not a species,
it is a religious
order or movement.
Their core belief is
that silence will fall
when the question
is asked.
What question?
The first question,
the oldest question
in the Universe,
hidden
in plain sight.
Yes, but what is
the question?
Unknown.
Oh, well, fat lot of use
that is, you big ginge.
Call yourselves
a records.
Agh!
Ahh!
The kidneys are always
the first to quit!
Ahh! I've had better,
you know.
Okay, he's finished.
Oh, my God.
[ Crying ]
Carter: Well, then,
let's do what we do.
Give her hell.
Ahhh!
Ohh! Ohhh! Ohhh! Ohh!
Amy, Rory.
Amy.
Can you hear me?
Yeah.
[ Feedback whines ]
You can talk
to him.
What do we do?
This is me.
This is me, actually
talking. What do we do?
[ Crying ]
Just stop them.
She's your daughter.
How? How?
How?
Just do it!
Privileges activated.
See?
She's your daughter.
Just stop them.
Rory: What
are you doing?
Pointing and thinking.
Get ready to run.
Right.
[ Alarm blares ]
You are unauthorized.
Your death will now be
implemented.
Okay, Captain,
release her now,
or I take down
the whole Teselecta.
Amy.
You can't.
They can.
[ Sonic screwdriver
pulsing ]
[ Alarm beeping ]
Rory, go!
All privileges
withdrawn.
What have you done?!
All life forms, prepare
for immediate decease.
You will experience
a tingling sensation
and then death.
- Shut it down!
- I'm trying!
Shut everything down!
Ah!
[ Crying ]
Please,
now, we have to save
your parents.
Don't run. Now,
I know you're scared,
but never run when
you're scared -- rule 7.
Please.
Remain calm while
your life is extracted.
Ah! Keep running!
Where?!
I don't know!
Just run!
Mother ship, mother ship,
get us out of here.
Emergency beamup,
now.
Everyone!
Only two life forms
remain.
This will be
rectified.
Where'd everyone go?
How can they just
disappear?
[ Whirring ]
Doctor,
can you hear us?
Doctor.
Doctor, help us!
Doctor,
help us!
Doctor, please!
Ah.
Uh!
Amy: Doctor!
Argh!
Help!
Melody:
Look at you.
You still care.
Amy: Doctor,
help!
Doctor, help us!
Please, help us!
It's impressive,
I'll give you that.
River, please.
Again!
Who is this River?
She's got to be
a woman.
Am I right?
[ Crying ]
Help me
save Amy and Rory.
Help me.
Tell me about her.
Go on.
Agh! Just!
Help me.
[ Error beeping ]
You are unauthorized.
Your death will now be
implemented.
You are unauthorized.
Your death will now be
implemented.
You are unauthorized.
Your death will now be
implemented.
I love you.
I love you, too.
You are unauthorized.
Your death will now be
implemented.
[ Engines ]
Doctor?
Doctor, you did it.
You did it.
[ Both laugh ]
I seem to be able
to fly her.
She showed me How.
She taught me.
The Doctor says
I'm the child
of the TARDIS.
What does he mean?
Where is he?
You can't die now.
I know
you don't die now.
Oh, Pond,
you've got a schedule
for everything.
It doesn't make
any sense.
Doctor, what do we do?
Come on.
How do
we help you?
Oh, I'm sorry, Rory,
you can't.
Nobody can.
Ponds,
listen to me.
I need to talk
to your daughter.
Find her.
Find River Song
and tell her something
for me.
Tell her what?
[ Whispering ]
[Crying] Well,
I'm sure she knows.
Who's
River Song?
Are you
still working
because I'm still
a relative?
Access files
on River Song.
Records available.
Show me her.
Show me River Song.
Now, he --
what did he say?
The Doctor gave you
a message
for River Song --
what was it?
What's
happening?
River, what
are you doing?
Just tell me --
the Doctor,
is he worth it?
Yes!
Yes, mm-hmm,
he is.
[ Gasping ]
River,
no.
[ Crying ]
What are you doing?
Hello, sweetie.
Hey.
Where am I?
Amy:
You're safe now.
Apparently, you used all
your remaining
regenerations
in one go.
You shouldn't have
done that. [Chuckle]
Mother,
I had to try.
I know.
He said no one
could save him,
but he must have known
I could.
The Doctor:
Rule 1 --
the Doctor lies.
Nurse: She just
needs to rest.
She'll be
absolutely fine.
The Doctor: No,
she won't.
She will be
amazing.
[ TARDIS engines ]
[ Warbling ]
So that's it,
we just leave her there?
The Sisters of
the Infinite Schism --
greatest hospital
in the Universe.
Yeah, but she's
our daughter, Doctor.
She's River
and she's our daughter.
[ Gently ]
Amy, I know,
but we have to let her
make her own way now.
We have too much
foreknowledge, it's --
dangerous thing,
foreknowledge.
What's that?
Nothing,
just some data
I downloaded
from the Teselecta --
very boring.
Doctor, River was brainwashed
to kill you, right?
Well, she did kill me
and then she used
her remaining lives
to bring me back.
As first dates go,
I'd say that was
mixed signals.
But...that stuff that
they put in her head,
is that gone now?
The River
that we know
in the future, she is
in prison for murder.
Whose murder?
[ "Next Stop Everywhere"
plays ]
[ Breathy chuckle ]
Will we
see her again?
Oh, she'll come
looking for us.
Amy: Yeah, but how?
How do people
even look for you?
Oh, Pond,
haven't you figured
that one out yet?
So, then, tell me,
why do you want
to study archaeology?
Well, to be perfectly
honest, Professor,
I'm looking
for a good man.
== sync, corrected by elderman ==